okay
well we should be getting the icsi
lombard
claims uh segment chief very soon
okay i think we can now i'll tell you
why we wanted to invite rci lombard so
there have been several reports of
overcharging by
private hospitals in tamil and the
tamilnadu government has
come and capped these charges uh what
does this mean for insurers and then
there have been separately of course
developments like
the cyclone in calcutta in west bengal
as well as the nisarga cyclone in
south of mumbai of course it spread the
city but all this would make life tough
for
insurers so we have us the management of
ics lombard
uh to make sense of all these moving
parts sanjay the chief
underwriting claims and reinsurance at
isis robot joins in
uh sanjay good morning thank you very
much for joining us well first
the covered impact i mean capping of
charges
i don't know how all this ties in with
you know a medical insurer like you
does it mean that there could be more
claims which will fall on you
no so it has to be very fair you know
you know we are here to take care of my
medical claims which call on us you know
that's what we are geared for you know
for these kind of uh situations
our policy covers it totally you know
entire industry you know it's good to
take this
these games of course you know uh what
you know we always look forward to is uh
you know rationalization of course
making making the affordable price you
know accessing health care so because in
these times of careers
sometimes the green shot also has
limited some insurance you may not have
brought a full sum and short policy
yeah also also at times you know you
know
uh whether we need to you know there
could be other elements also so
you know everything can be you know
utilized by coverage
so given that perspective it's important
to rationalize costs and be
able to charge you know you know
depending on the severity of disease and
you know the place where
you know treatment is taken and whether
there are other co-moderate conditions
or not
um so do you think this would mean
uh losses for a couple of quarters for
you i mean
um high
i mean calling of claims for the couple
of quarters
yes claims uh will be high you know so
you know we as you know
india is an infectious diseases country
so we always had infectious disease
this is getting bunched together that's
the only difference you know we always
have dengue and various other diseases
but uh you know so you're getting
balanced together so we you know it will
mean higher costs for us but
nevertheless
it provides sucker and more importantly
it also builds awareness you know you
know a health insurance is very
you know you know newly penetrated in
india so you know very little of private
health insurance has been treated in
india given the vast population
and hence it will you know mean that a
lot of people who can afford it will buy
you know health insurance going forward
actually that was my next question i
mean now there is this obsession with
the safety with health
that has suddenly come into the picture
because of covid and you know
uh the related lockdown uh do you
have you seen more business come through
um and
if yes what kind of growth are you
assuming uh say over the next six to 12
months
know so that's uh you know so we've seen
uh awareness
about health insurance you know
significantly certain amount of
inquiries
and you know you know various kind of uh
you know
advice regarding the kind of coverage
you know whether you know how we
discovered or not
you know there have been also you know
only products in the market people have
you know taken it up
so the efforts to introduce new standard
products in the market where the
regulator is coming around effects for
example so
we feel that obviously there could
update to what extent
and how big it will be you know it's a
function of various things including
affordability because also we are you
know going through a slow down you know
in that sense
but you know we definitely feel in the
long term you know the health insurance
awareness will grow and people will
definitely
you know pick up health insurance as one
of the key you know you know critical
you know
kind of fail-safe measures to be able to
make sure that such catastrophic events
are taken care of
sanjay how is this ant fun uh cyclone
affected you apparently it's one lakh
crore of losses
so that's the economic loss uh you know
uh you know uh
that's an estimated economic loss you
know we're not sure
you know how accurate that is it can
play out during the
you know the days ahead but having said
that insured losses always
as a percentage of the economic losses
have been very low in this country
because of the lack of penetration of
insurance
and so you know it's been you know
harvard around for all these cyclones so
far
how around three to four percent to ten
percent chennai was a slightly higher
because it was an urban center and you
know it
had a lot of coverage and so we're
hoping that uh
you know because the cyclone you know
didn't only hit calculated all the other
surrounding areas about 23 districts
so given that fact that there is low
penetration you know the
economic damage you know is not what
what translates into
insured losses uh so
it's something which uh the insurance
companies of course are geared to pay
these losses
everybody's gearing up we asses are have
been able to you know because of this
lockdown
you know sometimes like we've not been
able to physically reach the losses you
know aside to be able to assess damage
you know you know doing video surveys
and various other electronic means to be
able to reach out to the customer taking
care of
the scanned documents and trying to set
the laws as fast as possible
because we feel strongly that in this
times of lockdown where people have cash
flow issues is very important
that we play this kind of losses very
very fast
but uh okay how much are you making
money in terms of your investments
uh debt is not doing well but equity is
suddenly doing well
any uh commons net net are you in the
money
because it will be difficult to say at
this point of time you know by once the
quarter
closes i think we will uh be able to
take a stock of that and we'll be able
to publish our results based on that
but unfortunately out of time it's been
a hectic day in the markets
thank you very much indeed for joining
us we'll touch base later after we have
a better handle
thank you we as we find out on bazaar it